Finding aid for the Walter Jurmann papers, [1910]-1995 LSC.2271
UCLA Library Special Collections
Walter Jurmann papers
1910 - 2003
UCLA Library Special Collections
Jurmann, Walter
LSC.2271
5 linear feet (6 document boxes, 3 small flat boxes, and 1 large flat box)
.2 linear feet (1 shoebox)
5 audiovisual carriers (5 unprocessed VHS tapes)
Collection consists of material related to career of the composer Walter Jurmann, including scores, lyrics, business and personal papers, correspondence, photographs, and biographic items.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audio materials. Audio materials in this collection are restricted and require advance notice for use. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material, please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Yvonne Jurmann, 1988.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9919729393606533
Biographical note
Composer Walter Jurmann was born October 12, 1903, in Vienna, Austria. He began his career as a piano player in Austria and in 1927 moved to Berlin, where he became a pianist at the Eden Hotel. During his time in Berlin, Jurmann collaborated with the lyricist Fritz Rotter (1900-1984) and the Polish composer Bronislaw Kaper (1902-1983), creating a number of hit songs. In the early 1930s, Jurmann and Kaper also wrote songs for German and French films, and Jurmann wrote revues during a stay in Paris in 1933. He sometimes issued music under pseudonyms while working in Europe.
In 1934, Louis B. Mayer recruited Jurmann and Kaper for MGM's film productions, bringing them to Los Angeles. The pair wrote songs for the Marx Brothers' A Night at the Opera and A Day at the Races, and the films The Mutiny on the Bounty, Escapade, and San Francisco. Jurmann also composed music for several songs in the Judy Garland musical Presenting Lily Mars. By the mid-1940s, Jurmann had left the film industry, becoming a freelance composer. He later wrote a number of love songs, as well as songs for the cities of San Antonio, Houston, and Los Angeles. Jurmann died on June 17, 1971, while traveling in Budapest, Hungary.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of material related to the career of composer Walter Jurmann including scores, lyrics, business and personal papers, correspondence, photographs, and VHS tapes. Scores are primarily songs for films and popular songs in English and German. Also included are posthumous articles, clippings, programs, and other items concerning Jurmann's music. Much of collection, especially biographic material and some scores, was compiled by Jurmann's wife Yvonne Jurmann after his death.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series:
Series 1. Scores
Series 2. Lyrics
Series 3. Business and personal papers
Series 4. Correspondence
Series 5. Photographs
Series 6. Biographic material
Series 7. Sound recordings
Series 8. Ephemera.
Popular music.; Composers -- Archives.; Motion picture music.; Jurmann, Walter -- Archives
- Series 1. Scores, 1928-1982
  Scope and Contents note
  Scores are primarily published versions, though some manuscript and holograph scores, as well as reproductions, are present. Songs are arranged alphabetically by title in most subseries. Dates provided are usually copyright date of published version.
  - Subseries 1. Songs for film
    Scope and Content
    Scores for film songs are arranged alphabetically by film title. In most cases film titles are followed by the song title(s), then lyricist and composer. Items are in English, German, French, and Hungarian.
    - [Abenteuer am Lido]/ Adieu, es ist zu schön, um wahr zu sein; Worte Fritz Rotter, Musik Jurmann-Kaper (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abenteuer am Lido/ Adieu, es ist zu schön, um wahr zu sein; Wie schön ist diese Welt; Worte von Fritz Rotter, Musik von Jurmann-Kaper, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ein Ausflug in die Liebe/ Ohne Worte laßt uns scheiden, Triffst Du mein Süßes, Wenn der Frühling kommt ins Land; Worte von R. Bernauer und R. Oesterreicher, Musik von Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Chant du Destin/ Adieu; Ton Sourire Apaisé; Venetia, Ville D'amour; C'est L'amour qui M'enivre; Paroles de Ninon Steinhoff and André Legrand, Musique de Pierre Candel [Walter Jurmann], 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - [Chant du Destin]/ Adieu; Lyric by Ned Washington, Music by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A Day at the Races/ All God's Chillun Got Rhythm; Lyric by Gus Kahn, Music by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A Day at the Races/ Tomorrow is Another Day; Lyric by Gus Kahn, Melody by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ehe m.b.H/ Wer weint heut' aus Liebe Tränen; Ich frag' Madam', wann kommen wir zusamm'; Texte von Fritz Rotter, Musik von Dr. B. Kaper und Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Escapade/ You're All I Need; Lyric by Gus Kahn, Melody by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Es wird schon wieder besser/ 'S wird schon wieder besser, Wenn ein kleiner Zufall will; Texte Fritz Rotter, Musik Walter Jurmann und B. Kaper, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Everybody Sing/ Melody Farm; Words by Gus Kahn, Music by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Everybody Sing/ The One I Love; Words by Gus Kahn, Music by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Der glückliche Herr Fünf/ Tränen in der Geige, Schön ist das ganze Leben; Text von Fritz Rotter, Musik von B. Kaper u. W. Jurmann, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Her Majesty Love/ Because of You; Lyric by Al Dubin, Music by Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Her Majesty Love/ Though You're Not the First One; Lyric by Al Dubin, Music by Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Heut kommt's drauf an!/ Ich bin der Hans im Glück! Text von Fritz Rotter, Musik von Paul Mann u. Stephan Weissj In 24 Stunden kann soviel gescheh'n, Worte von Fritz Rotter, Musik von Jurmann und Kaper; Immer, wenn ich glücklich bin, muß ich schrecklich weinen; Text von Fritz Rotter, Musik von Jurmann und Kaper, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Heut kommt's drauf an!/ Mein Gorilla hat 'ne Villa im Zoo; Text von Peter Kuckuck, Musik von B. Kaper und W. Jurmann, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - His Butler's Sister/ In the Spirit of the Moment; Lyric by Bernie Grossman, Music by Walter Jurmann (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hochzeitsreise zu dritt!/ Signorina, ich liebe Dich; Wenn ich mal eine Dummheit mach; Text von Ernst Marishka, Musik von Walter Jurmann und B. Kaper, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ich glaub' nie mehr an eine Frau/ Deine Mutter bleibt immer bei Dir!; Worte und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ihre Majest ät die Liebe/ Du bist nicht die Erste!; Mein Glück bist Du!; Mein Fräulein, kennen Sie schon meinen Rhythmus?; Ich denk' an Mädi die ganze Nacht; Mensch, mach' Dir nichts draus!; Texte von Bernauer und Oesterreicher, Musik von Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Kind, ich freu' mich auf Dein Kommen/ Kind, ich freu' mich auf Dein Kommen und bin traurig wenn Du gehst, Der Matrose hat das größte Herz der Welt; Texte: Fritz Rotter, Musik: Walter Jurmann u. B. Kaper, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ein Lied für Dich/ Ninon, Signorina!; Texte Ernst Marischka u. Fritz Rotter, Musik Walter Jurmann und B. Kaper, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - [Ein Lied für Dich]/ Ninon; Lyric by Harold Adamson, Music by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Lucky Number/ Drop a Penny in the Wishing Well; Lyric by Paul Francis Webster, Music by Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Madame wünscht keine Kinder/ Ich geh' nie von Dir fort, denn ich lieb' Dich!; Nur Sport!; Musik von Walter Jurmann u. B. Kaper; Worte von Fritz Rotter u. Max Kolpe (2 copies), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Melodie der Liebe; Worte von Fritz Rotter, Musik von Dr. B. Kaper und Walter Jurmann (reproduction cover only), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Miracle on Main Street/ City of Angels; Lyric by Ralph Freed, Music by Walter Jurmann (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Mutiny on the Bounty/ Love song of Tahiti; Lyric by Gus Kahn, Melody by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Nice Girl?/ Beneath the Lights of Home; Music by Walter Jurmann, Lyrics by Bernie Grossman (published and holograph), 1941, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Nice Girl?/ Thank You America; Music by Walter Jurmann, Lyrics by Bernie Grossman (2 copies), 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - A Night at the Opera/ Cosi Cosa; Lyrics by Ned Washington, Melody by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Les Nuits Moscovites/ Natacha, On N'aime Qu'une Fois; Paroles de André de Badet, Musique de Kaper-Jurmann, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Les Nuits Moscovites/ Nuits Moscovites, En Avant; Paroles de André de Badet, Musique de Kaper-Jurmann, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - On a Volé un Homme/ Ni Mal Ni Bien, Un Regard de Femme; Paroles de René Pujol, Musique de W. Jurmann et B. Kaper, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Presenting Lily Mars/ Is It Really Love; Lyrics by Paul Francis Webster, Music by Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1942, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Presenting Lily Mars/ Russian Rhapsody; Lyrics by Paul Francis Webster, Music by Walter Jurmann, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - When I Look at You/ Presenting Lily Mars; Lyric by Paul Francis Webster, Music by Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - San Francisco/ San Francisco; Lyric by Gus Kahn, Melody by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann (signed by Jurmann), 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - San Francisco/ San Francisco; Paroles anglaises de Gus Kahn, Paroles françaises de André and Didier Mauprey, Musique de B. Kaper et W. Jurmann, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - San Francisco/ San Franciscso; Deutscher Text Fritz Rotter, Originaltext Gus Kahn, Musik Bronislaw Kaper u. Walter Jurmann (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - San Francisco/ San Francisco; Bronislaw Kaper és Walter Jurmann zenéje, Gus Kahn szövege, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - San Francisco/ San Franciso; Lyric by Gus Kahn, Melody by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann (reproduction cover only), [1939] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Seven Sweethearts/ You and the Waltz and I; Words by Paul Francis Webster, Music by Walter Jurmann (3 copies), 1942 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Skandal in der Parkstraße/ Du gefällst mir so! Text von Fritz Rotter, Musik von Walter Jurmann und B. Kaper (2 copies), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Skandal in der Parkstraße/ Ganz ohne Liebe wär' das Leben so bescheiden; Text von Fritz Rotter, Musik von Walter Jurmann und B. Kaper (2 copies), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Thousands Cheer/ Three Letters in the Mailbox; Lyric by Paul Francis Webster, Music by Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Three Smart Girls/ My Heart is Singing; Lyric by Gus Kahn, Music by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Three Smart Girls/ Someone to Care for Me; Lyric by Gus Kahn, Music by Bronislaw Kaper and Walter Jurmann, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Too Many Husbands/ Tvrolka; Lyric by Bernie Grossman, Music by Walter Jurmann, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Too Many Husbands/ Waltz; Lyric by Bernie Grossman, Music by Walter Jurmann, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Tout Pour L'amour/ Ninon Quand Tu Me Souris; Version concert paroles de Ch. L. Pothier, Version film paroles de Georges Clouzot et Serge Veber, Musique de B. Kaper et W. Jurmann (2 copies), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Tout Pour L'amour/ O Madona! (O Madonna!); Paroles de Ch. L. Pothier, Musique de B. Kaper et W. Jurmann, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Tulip Time in Michigan/ Little Tingle Tangle Toes; Lyric by Paul Francis Webster; Music by Walter Jurmann, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Typee/ Shadows on the Starlit Waters; Lyric by Ned Washington, Music by B. Kaper and W. Jurmann, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - ...Und das ist die Hauptsache!/ Manchmal möcht' man so gern' Nur meine Leidenschaft, die macht mich so beliebt!; Musik von Walter Jurmann, Gesangstexte von Fritz Rotter, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - [Unidentified]/ All the World is Waiting for Romance; Lyric by Bernie Grossman, Music by Walter Jurmann, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Unidentified]/ Believe My Heart; Lyric by Bernie Grossman, Music by Walter Jurmann, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Unidentified]/ Doing Things for You; Lyric by Bernie Grossman, Music by Walter Jurmann, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Unidentified]/ The Lights of Picadilly Will Shine Again; Lyrics by Bernie Grossman, Music by Walter Jurmann (holograph and reproduction), 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - [Unidentified]/ Two Hearts Under One Umbrella; Lyrics by Paul Francis Webster, Music by Walter Jurmann (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 2. Stage works
    - Un Baiser de Femme Sous un Ciel de Feu/ Paroles de Henri Varna, Léo Lelièvre, Marc Cab; Musique de Jurmann-Kaper, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - C'est Chez Nous/ Paroles de Henri Varna, Léo Lelièvre & Marc Cab; Musique de Jurmann-Kaper, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - C'est Ton Amour/ Paroles de Henri Varna, Louis Poterat; Musique de Jurmann-Kaper, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Vivons L'amour! Vivons La Vie!/ Paroles de Henri Varna, Léo Lelièvre, Marc Cab; Musique de Jurmann-Kaper, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Windy City/ Words by Paul Webster; Music by Walter Jurmann, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
    - As the Wind Bloweth [from] Windy City/ Lyrics by Paul Francis Webster; Music by Walter Jurmann, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Don't Ever Run Away from Love [from] Windy City/ Lyrics by Paul Francis Webster; Music by Walter Jurmann, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Where Do We Go From Here [from] Windy City/ Lyrics by Paul Francis Webster; Music by Walter Jurmann, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 3. Choral arrangements
    - A Better World to Live In; for mixed chorus, SATB, with accompaniment/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4. Piano works
    - Parade March of the 6th Ferrying Command/ Walter Jurmann; arranged by P. A. Marquardt (holograph), 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 5. Other songs
    Material includes published scores, manuscripts, reproductions, verses, and lyrics.
    - 21 Lieder und Chansons/ Walter Jurmann (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Am Schönen Titicacasee/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Auf Dein Wohl Trink Mit Mir/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Die Augen der Liebe Seh'n Alias so Schön/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Ausgerechnet Donnerstag/ Text von Fritz Rotter; Musik von Walter Jurmann, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beginn den Tag Mit Liebe; Lass' Dich versöhnen; [Und Ich] Klopf, klopf, klopf an Deine Türe (holograph) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - A Better World to Live In/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann (published, holograph, transparency), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Chéri, Tu Reviendras/ Paroles de André Mauprey; Musique de Pierre Candel [Walter Jurmann], 1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Deine Liebe ist wie der Frühling/ Words Music alter Jurmann, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Denk' daran/ Worte u. Musik Walter Jurmann, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Du bist in meinem Leben die erste Sensation!/ Text von Fritz Rotter; Musik von W. Jurmann u. B. Kaper (2 copies), 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Du liebst mich nicht mehr/ Text von Fritz Rotter; Musik von Bob Henders [Jurmann-Kaper ?], 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Einmal im Leben/ Text von Beda; Musik von Walter Jurmann, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Es war nur eine kleine Träumerei/ Worte und Music Walter Jurmann, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Have Faith/ Music u. Worte Walter Jurmann, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Houston/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann (transparency and score), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Ich folge Dir, bis an's Ende der Welt/ Musik u. Worte Walter Jurmann, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ich hab' im Frühling nur Dich geküßt/ Fritz Rotter u. Walter Jurmann, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ich lieg' so gern im grünen Gras/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ich trag dein Bild/ Worte Musik Walter Jurmann, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ich weiß schon längst, daß Du mich heimlich lieb hast!/ Text von Fritz Rotter; Musik von Walter Jurmann, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - If There Were Dreams for Sale/ Lyrics, Ruth Freed; Music, Walter Jurmann (holograph) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - In Deinem Rosengarten/ Worte u. Music Walter Jurmann, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - In Dich bin ich verliebt!/ Musik Worte Walter Jurmann, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - In Dich hab' ich mich verliebt!/ von Fritz Rotter u. Walter Jurmann, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - In meiner Einsamkeik/ Worte u. Music Walter Jurmann, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Keiner hat Dich je so heiss wie ich geliebt/ von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann (3 copies), 1929 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Kennst Du den Weg zum Paradies..?/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1930 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Eine kleine Reise im Frühling mit Dir!/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Lach' mich nicht aus!/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Liebe bei Kerzenlicht/ Worte u. Music Walter Jurmann, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Linger Just a Little Longer/ Words by Bernie Grossmann; Music by Walter Jurmann (holograph), 1951 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Long Live Israel/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann (manuscript and transparency) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles, the City I Love/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann (manuscript and reproduction), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles/ Words by Arthur Hamilton; Music by Walter Jurmann (published score, reproductions of three versions), 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Mein schönes Wien/ Musik Worte Walter Jurmann, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Mein schönes Wien/ Text Josef Kaderka; Musik Walter Jurmann, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ein modernes Wiegenlied/ Worte und Musik Walter Jurmann, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - My Heart is an Island/ Lyric by Ruth Freed; Music by Walter Jurmann, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - My Heart Ran Away with the Moon/ W. Jurmann (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - My Unforgettable You/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Nimm Dir mit aus Wien/ Text Hans Werner; Musik Walter Jurmann (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Nur eine Stunde mehr/ Worte und Music Walter Jurmann, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ohne Erinnerungen/ Text u. Musik Walter Jurmann; Klavierbearbeitung Herbert Seiter, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Olga, Tochter der Wolga/ Text von Artur Rebner; Musik von Walt Jurmann, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Only One Heart, Nischninovgorod, Poor Baby, Deanna, [unidentified] (verses) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Reg' mich nicht auf, Johanna!/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Remember Pearl Harbor/ Lyric Grossman; Music W. Jurmann (holograph) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Remember the Seventh of December/ Lyrics Bernie Grossman; Music Walter Jurmann (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Rêves d'Amour/ Musique de Pierre Candel [Walter Jurmann]; Paroles de André de Badet, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Sag' einmal "Ja" zu mir, was liegt schon dran!/ Text von Fritz Rotter; Musik von Walt Jurmann, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - San Antonio (The City of So Many Charms)/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann (transparency and five published copies), 1966, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Der schönste Traum, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Sehr geschätzes Fräulein Laura/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann (2 copies), 1932 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Eine Sommernacht am Meer / Text von Fritz Rotter; Musik von Bob Handers [Jurmann-Kaper], 1932 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Einen Sonntag ohne Sorgen/ Text von Fritz Rotter; Musik von Walter Jurmann und B. Kaper, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Ein spanischer Tango und ein Mädel wie Du../ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Spiel mir ein Lied auf der Geige../ Text von Fritz Rotter; Musik von Walter Jurmann, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - This is My Heart/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Trink Dich gesund/ Musik von Erich Walter Schmidt [Jurmann-Kaper]; Worte von Peter Schattner [Fritz Rotter], 1933 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Vergesse Deine Sorgen/ Worte und Music Walter Jurmann, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Vielen Dank../ Musik u. Worte Walter Jurman, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Wagging on the Doorstep; Weg Weg / Lyrics by Alfred Dunning; Music by Walter Jurmann, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Was weisst denn Du, wie ich verliebt bin/ Verse von Fritz Rotter; Musik von Walter Jurmann, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Der Weg zu Deinem Herzen/ Worte und Musik Walter Jurmann (also Modernes Wiegen Lied on one sheet), 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Weißt Du was Du kannst--mich am Nachmittag besuchen../ von Rotter, Jurmann und Egen, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Welcome to the Hemisfair/ Words and Music by Walter Jurmann (two holographs, one transparency), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Wenn der Maximilian Tango mit Dir tanzt/ Text und Musik von Fritz Rotter und Walter Jurmann, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Wenn ich den Isak ein bißchen pisak/ Text von Artur Rebner; Musik von Walt Jurmann, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Wien ist wieder Wien; Wien bleibt immer Wien/ Text und Musik Walter Jurmann, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Fragment, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 6. Music by others
    - Songs from musical Jump for Joy: Nothin', The Tune of the Hickory Stick, The Brown-skin Gal in the Calico Gown, Chocolate Shake, Jump for Joy, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - La Femme d'une Nuit/ Paroles de Léo Lelièvre; Musique de Michel Levine, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Boogie Woogie Piano Styles no. 2, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series 2. Lyrics, 1966, undated
  Lyrics are undated unless otherwise noted.
  - Subseries 1. Lyrics by Jurmann
    Includes handwritten and typed drafts, and final versions.
    - All I've Got Is You (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - All the World is Waiting for Love and Romance (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Angelina; Teach Me How to Love You (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Annemarie (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - A Better World To Live In (San Antonio on reverse)/ Let's Make This Great Big World A Better Place to Live In (On the Bumpy Road to Romance on reverse)/ A World We Can Believe In (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Blue Monday (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Deine Liebe ist wie der Frühling (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Denk Daran (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Do It Now (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Es war nur eine kleine Traeumerei (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Forever and Ever (Love Me on reverse) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Have Faith in America (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Houston, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - I Found My Sunshine in the Rain (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ich folge Dir, bis ans Ende der Welt (Ein modernes Wiegenlied on reverse) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ich mache mir Vorwürfe täglich (first line) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ich trag' Dein Bild in meinem Herzen; Mein schönes Wien; Ohne Erinnerungen; Wien ist wieder Wien (Box 4, Folder 2)